

Andras Schmelczer www.schmelczer.dev

andras@schmelczer.dev

+31633147440



The Hague 💿

I'm passionate about designing and building large-scale systems, especially in the context of NLP. I'm excited to take my part in connecting people and providing them with Al/ML solutions along with the necessary integrations, which were unimaginable even a decade ago.

With a master's degree in Computer Science and more than six years of professional software engineering experience, I can confidently undertake any challenge.

Professional experience

Feb 2022 – present

Chief Technology Officer

ScoutinScience B.V.

- Assessed and identified technological opportunities and threats
- Architected a cohesive platform for merging all our projects
- Assembled a team and led the development of this platform
- Streamlined processes and strengthened security across the organisation

Feb 2021 – Feb 2022

Senior Software Engineer

ScoutinScience B.V.

- Researched, designed, and continuously improved an explainable NLP pipeline for ranking academic publications based on their tech-transfer potential
- Gathered manual annotations from experts and developed explainable ML models for aspect-based summarisation of scientific papers
- Implemented business logic (ASP.NET, EF), maintained databases (PostgreSQL, MongoDB), and orchestrated deployments (GitHub Actions, K8s)

Jan 2020 -Oct 2020

Software Engineer

ALLWIN Informatika Kft.

- Built a multitude of microservices for an accessible AI/ML platform
- Implemented ML glue code and business logic in Python and ASP.NET
- Configured CI/CD pipelines using Azure DevOps and a large-scale deployment with Kubernetes
- Gained valuable experience in the research, integration, and production-ready deployment of AI/ML systems with a focus on image processing

Apr 2019 – Full Stack Developer Nov 2019 – Avatas Innovetive Le

Avatao Innovative Learning Kft.

- Created interactive tutorials and quizzes about secure .NET coding
- Acquired a great deal of experience working with Flask and Angular
- Created a full-stack app for innovatively assessing Cybersecurity expertise

Jul 2018 – Apr 2019

Software Developer

The Laboratory of Cryptography and System Security (CrySyS)

- Created an online 3D city simulation with Unity exposing an API for interacting with its traffic lights which influences the drivers
- Devised a mathematical simulation of a nuclear facility's cooling system (with a GUI and editor) by designing two graph algorithms
- NumPy, SciPy, Flask, HTML5, JavaFX

Oct 2016 – Apr 2019

Web developer

Freelance

- Designed, built, and successfully delivered various websites and full-stack applications
- JavaScript, TypeScript, CSS, SASS, Linux

Education

2021 -

2022

Computer Science MSc — cum laude (8.8 / 10) Leiden University

- Completed the Advanced Computing and Systems specialisation focusing on distributed and cloud computing
- Developed a strong background in AI/ML through my electives: image processing, information retrieval, reinforcement learning, modern game AI, and text mining
- Guided groups during the orientation weeks for two years & mentored students helping them pursue their academic goals and adjust to their new lives abroad

2017 – 2021

Computer Engineering BSc — summa cum laude (4.99/5)

Budapest University of Technology and Economics

- Completed the software development specialisation track, which heavily focused on DDD, OOP, and 3D graphics and Agile development and organisational practices
- Led the development team at Károly Simonyi College for Advanced Studies for two semesters
- TA for the Embedded Operating Systems laboratory practice and RA for Databases

Hobbies

- Cycling
- Coffee
- Badminton
- Photography
- loT & shaders

Certificates

- English C1IELTS Academic 8.0
- Driving license